# Hrisikesh Kumar (Full Stack Azure Developer)

hrisikeshkumar@gmail.com

**©** 8944022202

New Delhi, India

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hrisikesh--kumar/



# Summary

Passionate about learning new technologies, trust on excellence and hardworking, being efficient & productive for the development of organization as well as diversifying my professional skill-set by providing best solutions to the clients.

9+ years of experience in software development using Microsoft Azure as cloud environment and front end as well as back-end technologies.

Excellent Knowledge in Cloud technologies: Microsoft Azure IAAS, PAAS services like App Service, Azure Active Directory, Storage Accounts, Azure SQL Server, Azure Function, Logic App etc.

Excellent knowledge in .NET technologies: .NET Core 6.0, C#, Asp.Net MVC, ADO.Net, Web Forms, Web services

**Cloud Technologies:** Azure VM, Blob storage, App Service, Azure Active Directory, Storage Accounts, Azure SQL Server, Azure Function, Logic App etc.

**Frontend Technologies**: .NET Core 6.0, C#, Asp.Net MVC, ADO.Net, Web Forms, Web services, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS.

**Backend Technologies**: Excellent knowledge in database design and programming with Microsoft SQL Server.

#### Certification

AZ-104: Azure Administrator Associate AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

AZ-204: Azure Developer Associate DP-900: Azure Data Fundamentals

AI-900: Azure AI Fundamentals

### **Projects**

**Inventory Management Software:** Understanding user requirements, accordingly design, develop, and providing technical support to that project.

Technology Stack: Asp.net MVC Core 6.0, Java Script, JQuery, Azure Sql, Azure AD authentication, Blob service

**Membership Portal Management Software:** Understanding user requirements, accordingly design, develop, maintain and providing technical support to that project

Technology Stack: Asp.net MVC Core 3.0, Java Script, JQuery, Azure Sql, Azure AD authentication

**Employee Performance Management Software:** Understanding user requirements, accordingly design, develop, and providing technical support to that project.

Technology Stack: Asp.net MVC Core 3.0, Java Script, JQuery, Sql server 2019, Azure AD authentication, Blob service

**Student Registration & Management Software:** Understanding user requirements, design, develop, maintain and providing technical support to that project.

Technology Stack: Asp.net MVC 5, Java Script, JQuery, Sql server 2014, Web services, Html, CSS

**Payroll Management software** Understanding user requirements, design, develop, maintain and providing technical support to that project.

Technology Stack: Asp.net MVC 5, Java Script, JQuery, Sql server 2012, Web services, Html, CSS

**Tea Management ERP** Understanding user requirements, design, develop, maintain and providing technical support to that project.

Technology Stack: Asp.Net Webform, Java Script, JQuery, Sql server 2012, Web services, Html, CSS

## **School Management Software**

Design, develop, maintain and providing technical support to that project

Technology Stack: Asp.Net Webform, Java Script, JQuery, Sql server 2008)

## **Experience**

**Programmer,** Institute of Company Secretaries of India

Successfully develop and Implement lots of software project.

Contact: Mr. Praveen Kumar – 9911726230

Programmer, Ray Computech Pvt. Ltd

successfully develop and maintain Tea Management ERP

which is used by lots of Tea Company. Contact: Mr. Pradeep - 9804403498

Junior Software Developer, Dolphin InfoTech

Successfully Develop school Management Software.

Contact: Mr. Rakesh Ji - 9831576679

08/2016 – present | Delhi - NCR, India

07/2014 – 02/2016 | Kolkata, India

01/2014 - 07/2014 | Hooghly, India

# **Education**

**Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering,** West Bengal University of Technology

10+2 Standard (Science Stream),

West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education

10Th Standard, West Bengal Board of Secondary Education

07/2009 - 05/2013 West Bengal, India

07/2005 – 04/2007

West Bengal, India

05/2003 - 04/2005

West Bengal, India

#### Languages

English • • • • Bengali

Hindi ● ● ●

#### Interests

Leaning New Technology, Reading Books, Exploring business model of various company.

# **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the details and information given above are complete and true to the best of my knowledge.

Hrisikesh kumar New Delhi